ISRAEL OLIVEIRA

WEB DEVELOPER SINCE 2007

CONTACT

1

+351 913 558 933



raloliver.ws@gmail.com



Fundão, Portugal



linkedin.com/in/raloliver

EXPERTISE

WEB DEVELOPMENT

INFORMATION ARCHITECTURE

USER EXPERIENCE

DIGITAL MARKETING

WEB DESIGN

EDUCATION

BACHELOR

University of North of Paraná - Brazil 2013 – 2016 (Incomplete degree)

ENGLISH

WiseUp Language School - Brazil 2013 - 2015 (Professional Level)

FRENCH

In Company Formations – Portugal 2020 (Basic Level)

PROFILE

I am a front-end developer interested in working with another Javascript framework. I am most comfortable working with Javascript, Typescript, and Angular, however, I am open to working with VueJS. In my next role, I want to continue as a front-end developer, mostly with unit tests, e2e tests, bug fixes, and working on legacy front-end code.

My ideal next job is one where I can get experience with another Javascript framework (preferably VueJS) and work a hybrid way or on-site... I miss the office.

For the companies that do not have a subsidiary in Portugal, I'll wait for UE citizenship before applying for opportunities abroad.

EXPERIENCE

FRONT END DEVELOPER

Doutor Finanças | Remotely - Portugal | 2022 - Present

Helping people to manage their money. For the moment I working on a project that enables the possibility to make a short-way contact by chat, where the client can send files and receive details about their process. We develop a PWA, and at this moment we focus on incrementing the chat experience with more features and maintaining the good performance of the web app.

My main tasks involve creating new features, fixing bugs, and writing unit tests.

Technological environment: JIRA, Confluence, CI/CD, Rest API, POCS, Microservices, Scrum, Git, Docket, PHP, Laravel, Angular, Angular CLI, Typescript, RxJS, NgRx, NX, JavaScript, Jest, Spectator, HTML, SASS, CSS, and GitHub.

FRONT END DEVELOPER

Basecone | Remotely - Portugal | 2021 - 2022

Giving more time to the accountant, I have been working on this huge platform, which is an important part of the integration process to control the authorization flow and assign invoices automatically to the right users.

The web portal has an automated workflow, where it is possible to upload a document (or send it by email, even scan by mobile application), that it recognized the data by OCR and provides the essential tools to the accountants to handle their routines in the fiscal process.

As a frontend developer, I have been working on new features using the redux pattern in Angular way with Storeon and I am responsible for ensuring the code coverage above 80%, writing the unit tests using that connected with the business rules, also implementing the End-to-End tests with the TestCafe library.

Technological environment: JIRA, Confluence, CI/CD, Rest API, SPIKE, Microservices, Scrum, Git, Docket, Visual Studio, SQL Server, NodeJS, npm, Angular, Angular CLI, Typescript, JavaScript, Jasmine, TestCafe, HTML, SASS, CSS, and GitHub.

TRAININGS

How to Manage a Remote Team

Cousera

2023 (Certificate of conclusion)

Certificado De Competências Pedagógicas

IEFP

2021 (Certificate of conclusion)

UX Design Formation

Mergo User Experience – Brazil 2015 (<u>Certificate of conclusion</u>)

Information Architecture

Mergo User Experience – Brazil 2015 (Cetificate of conclusion)

INTERESTS

PARENTHOOD

PRIVACY

GAMING

SKILLS

JAVASCRIPT

+5 Years

ANGULAR

+5 Years

TYPESCRIPT

+5 Years

RXJS

+5 Years

UNIT TESTS

3 Years

EXPERIENCE - CONTINUING

FRONT END DEVELOPER

Agap2IT | Remotely - Portugal | 2021

Working in a service for collection, verification, and storage of data and documents. It is for financial and non-financial institutions subject to AML (Anti-Money Laundering)/KYC (Know Your Customer) professional obligations and also all-natural and legal persons by a centralized KYC repository.

Involved in all stages of a feature delivery: grooming sessions, check details from acceptance criteria and do the code development. Besides, I do code reviews and keep JIRA up to date. Sometimes it is necessary to deep dive into the code to avoid repeat me and apply the best approach for a project that's running for a couple of years.

Technological environment: JIRA, SonarQube, CI/CD, Rest API, SPIKE, Microservices, Scrum, Git, Spring Boot, IntelliJ IDEA, MongoDB, Angular, Angular CLI, Typescript, JavaScript, HTML, SASS, CSS, and Gitlab.

FRONT END DEVELOPER

Altran | Fundão - Portugal | 2020 - 2021

In the first project I worked on, it was a POC that is an extension of in-car entertainment and allows the driver to control climate comfort. In the most recent project, the main goal was the construction of a multi branding and multilingual frontend application to the customer, that runs in a desktop, mobile, and kiosks. The project consisted of a companion web app that enabled the customer to rent machines and the dealers to configure all stuff to the customer, such as booking, portal, and institutional content. At the last project I working on FIRE project for Proximus BE, the project had the main goal, to start a fiber campaign that sends sales agents door to door to buildings where Proximus can offer services on fiber connectivity.

My tasks were the development of the application using Angular 7 and participated at meetings, grooming, and planning with managers, client, designer, backend, and DevOps team, and also, I commitment to all SCRUM routines and ceremonies.

Technological environment: JIRA, SonarQube, Microsoft Azure, Rest API, MVVM, MVP, Kanban, Scrum, Git, Angular, Angular CLI, Typescript, JavaScript, HTML, SASS, CSS, indexedDB, Jasmine, Responsive Web Design, SCP, Simply and Gitlab.

FRONT END DEVELOPER

Radek Systems | Curitiba - Brazil | 2018 - 2020

At this company, I worked on a project named "Fidelidade" and the main goal of this PWA is to give cashback to the client. That project was created for MADERO, it is a huge network in Brazil and has something about 200 restaurants. We use Javascript and the most modern Chrome APIs: PWA, push notifications, offline approach, offline and online data synchronization (indexedDB), reactive programming (RxJS), creation, and communication of components through state management. Among so many other routines that involve client-side-development.

Technological environment: JIRA, SonarQube, Microsoft Azure, Rest API, MVVM, MVP, Kanban, Scrum, Git, Angular, Angular CLI, Typescript, Javascript, HTML, SASS, CSS, indexedDB, Jasmine, API Rest, Responsive Web Design, SCP, Simply and Gitlab.

SKILLS - CONTINUING

GIT

+5 Years

HTML/CSS

+10 Years

RESPONSIVE WEB DESIGN

+5 Years

NODEIS

+5 Years

READ RECENTLY

FRIDAY IS THE NEW SATURDAY

Author: Pedro Gomes

THE BURNOUT SOCIETY

Author: Byung-Chul-Han

NONVIOLENT COMMUNICATION

Author: Marshall B. Rosenberg

GET PROGRAMMING WITH IS NEXT

Author: JD Isaacks

FAMILY DRIVEN FAITH

Author: Voddie Baucham Jr.

LEARNING JAVASCRIPT DATA STRUCTURES AND ALGORITHMS

Author: Loiane Groner

THE ADVERSITY ADVANTAGE

Author: Erik Weihenmayer and Paul Stoltz

QUIET: THE POWER OF INTROVERTS

Author: Susan Cain

EXPERIENCE - CONTINUING

FRONT END DEVELOPER

Gatefy Security Solutions | Curitiba - Brazil | 2018

The main goal of this project was to handle inbox mail security. Create a component that is responsible for mark an email as a ham, spam, porn or another type.

I worked on an inbox feature, that's like a Gmail inbox, and on this project, we use a lit bit of redux in angular way, and the most complex thing on this component is that: the user can select more than one email and mark determined type, but if one of that email has a different type, the component has should be maintained that type, and if both have the same type, that component should maintain the same type, something like a Gmail does when mark as read or not.

Technological environment: MVC, Scrum, Bitbucket, Trello, REST, Angular, Angular CLI, CSS, Git, HTML, JavaScript, npm, PHP, Responsive Web Design, Typescript and Web API.

FRONT END DEVELOPER

GO.K Digital Innovation | Remotely - Brazil | 2017 - 2018

The main goal of this project was to create a growing artificial intelligence, that's able to learn with the user's inputs, and with this, help the users to create marketing campaigns for the correct product-market fit.

I worked on in an MVP with some features, such as login, creation account, recover password, dashboard with charts and list of reports and segments, and a feature to record audio from a user and write down what he said, and after that, create a new campaign based on what he just talked about it.

Technological environment: POC, Scrum, Bitbucket, JIRA, REST, Axure Prototype, Invision Prototype, Angular, Angular CLI, SCSS, Git, HTML, JavaScript, npm, Responsive Web Design, Typescript and Browser API.

FRONT END DEVELOPER

LeadLovers Tecnologia | Curitiba - Brazil | 2014 - 2018

For four years, I worked at this startup (something like eGoi), and at that place, I learned a lot about digital marketing automation and as a front-end developer, I worked with designers and developers, and all issues always involved how to provide the best user experience for the clients. I've gone through all departments in this company: creating page templates, as a scrum master, customizing websites with WordPress, manage affiliates, group administrator on Facebook, creating templates, design team lead, facilitator working on development culture, monitoring user experience with research and team performance with spreadsheets, KPIs and checkpoints with the product team.

In 2014 I worked as a front end and web designer, to make landing pages and websites for the marketing department. In 2015 I continued working as a front-end developer (for the marketing department) and produced some content such as documentation, tutorials, videos for the YouTube channel, and help some users on issues about code. In 2016 I continued working as a front-end developer and help a product team as a team lead, mainly working on user experience with designers and developers.

In 2016 I worked as Team Lead and I received good feedback when the HR made a 360 anonymous research. See here what my colleagues say about me.

From 2017 until 2019 I worked only as a front-end developer, mainly in a new internal project and two new startups in the company as you can see on my YouTube channel.

Technological environment: MVP, MVC, MVVW, Azure, Scrum, Git GitHub Trello, Asana, REST, SOA, Cloud, Digital Marketing, User Experience, Lean Startup, Scrum, Adobe Photoshop, Angular, Angular Material, Angular JS, API Rest, Bootstrap, Content marketing, CSS 3, Git, GitHub, HTML 5, JavaScript, jQuery, npm, Team Lead, Typescript, WebApi, Webpack and WordPress.

GITHUB PROJECTS

RECNOTES (Repository Link)

This is just an app to practice concepts about React in a practical and beautiful way.

NESTJS-TASKS (Repository Link)

Task Managment Application.

TYPE-NODE (Repository Link)

This API was made with Typescript, follows the TDD approach, and also uses the best design patterns.

PATTERNS (Repository Link)

Practicing the most famous Java Patterns.

JEST (Repository Link)

Show me the code, and I show you the test...

JS-FUNCTIONAL (Repository Link)

Replicate the most famous functional patterns with vanilla JavaScript.

REFACTOR (Repository Link)

The best way to refactor JavaScript applications.

NG9 (Repository Link)

Just a simple test to run angular version 9.

NGRX-BLOG (Repository Link)

Angular reactive with ngRx.

TYPE-NODE-CRUD (Repository Link)

Simple CRUD with NodeJS, TypeScript and MongoDB.

XCHANGE-CONVERTER (Repository Link)

A CLI to convert EUR to any currency provided.

SOCIAL







in linkedin.com/in/raloliver

AWARDS

FEEDBACK 360

On 2016 I worked as Team Lead and I received a good feedback when the HR made a 360 anonymous research. See here what my colleagues talked about me.

RECENT ONLINE TRAINING

HOW TO MANAGE A REMOTE TEAM

Coursera | Finished: 18/04/2023 | 10 hours | Language: Portuguese Certificate of conclusion

CERTIFICADO DE COMPETÊNCIAS PEDAGÓGICAS (Certificate)

IEFP | Finished: 17/02/2021 | Number: F708206/2021 | Language: Portuguese Certificate of conclusion

ANGULAR ARCHITECTURE AND BEST PRACTICES

Pluralsight | Finished: 04/10/2022 | 5 hours | Language: English Certificate of conclusion

APRENDA A TESTAR APLICAÇÕES JAVASCRIPT

Fábio Vedovelli | Finished: 16/09/2022 | 20 hours | Language: Portuguese Certificate of conclusion

SYMFONY PARTE 1: CRIAÇÃO DE UMA API RESTFUL

Alura | Finished: 30/08/2022 | 6 hours | Language: Portuguese Certificate of conclusion

DEVOPS & AGILE CULTURE

FIAP | Finished: 27/07/2021 | 60 hours | Language: Portuguese Certificate of conclusion

IAVASCRIPT: DE PADRÕES A UMA ABORDAGEM FUNCIONAL

Alura | Finished: 07/08/2021 | 10 hours | Language: Portuguese Certificate of conclusion

RECOMENDATIONS

KAYNA OLIVEIRA (Web Fullstack Developer at Talmix)

While working with Israel on Altran I got to experience his work as a developer. The most striking point for me was his thoroughness and reliability. If a work item was allocated to Israel I could be sure that that problem would be solved to the best of his abilities and with as much attention to details as possible.

KALINE MATTOS (Web Designer at Coolbet)

Ral (as we call him) is an excellent professional, he is always leaving his comfort zone and learning new things. He was a mentor, a friend, a confidant.

An unusual person, always a definite goal. Your projects always come out flawless and optimized. I miss to work with him and exchange experiences.

LUCAS FABOSSI (Product Designer at Localiza&Co)

Israel is one of the most fantastic people I've ever worked with. It is constantly updating itself, sharing knowledge and news. Think of the team and the company honestly and unselfishly. He does not hesitate to test, being always ready to put into practice the ideas and knowledge acquired. An inspiring professional!